Guide to the Bella C. Landauer Collection of Business and Advertising Ephemera 1700-1990 PR 31
New-York Historical Society
- Series II: LOOSE EPHEMERA
  - Subseries I: SMALL EPHEMERA
    - Waterworks (Offsite-box 123)
    - Wool (Offsite-box 123)
  - Subseries II: MEDIUM EPHEMERA
    - Advertising (Offsite-box 124)
    - Agriculture (Offsite-box 124)
    - Animals (Offsite-box 124)
    - Art (Offsite-box 124)
    - Beverages (Offsite-box 124)
      Alcoholic: Temperance material, Miscellaneous
      Non-alcoholic: Cocoa, Coffee, Soda Water, Tea
    - Building (Offsite-box 124)
      Awnings and Shades, Marble, Paint, Plumbing, Miscellaneous
    - Business (Offsite-box 124)
      Banks
    - Clubs and Societies (Offsite-box 125)
    - Clothing (Offsite-box 125)
      Ladies, Men, Milliners, Shoes and Boots
    - Druggists (Offsite-box 125)
      New York City, New England, Miscellaneous
    - Drugs and Medicines (Offsite-box 126)
      Blood Purifiers: Sarsaparilla, Miscellaneous
      Children's
      Digestives; Ex-Lax, Miscellaneous
      External Remedies
      Female Disorders
      Indian Remedies
      Medicinal Food
      Pain
      Respiratory
      Vermifuges
    - Dry Goods (Offsite-box 127)
      Merchants and miscellaneous products
    - Electricity (Offsite-box 127)
    - Food (Offsite-box 127)
      Baking, Bread and Crackers
      Candy
      Flour and Yeast
      Fruit and Produce
    - Food (Offsite-box 128)
      Grocers - retail
      Ice Cream and Ice
      Lard and Meat
    - Furniture (Offsite-box 128)
    - Hardware (Offsite-box 128)
    - Hotels and Restaurants (Offsite-box 128)
    - Household (Offsite-box 129)
      Cleansers
      Cord, Rope and Twine
      Glues and Cement
      House Furnishings
      Silver and Cutlery
      Laundry
      Polishes – Stove
    - Insurance (Offsite-box 129)
    - Jewelry (Offsite-box 129)
    - Leather Goods (Offsite-box 129)
    - Military (Offsite-box 129)
      Civil War
      Spanish American War
      World War II
    - Oil (Offsite-box 130)
    - Paper (Offsite-box 130)
    - Periodicals (Offsite-box 130)
      Magazines:
      A-C
      D-K
      L-O
      P-Z
      Atlantic
      Frank Leslie's Illustrated
      Inland Printer
      Jeness Miller Monthly
      Peterson
      To Date
      Theater
      Young Ladies' Journal
    - Periodicals (Offsite-box 131)
      Newspapers
    - Photography (Offsite-box 131)
    - Printing and Engraving (Offsite-box 131)
      Engravers
      Printers
    - Professions and Occupations (Offsite-box 131)
    - Publications (Offsite-box 132)
      Publishers
    - Real Estate (Offsite-box 132)
    - Religion (Offsite-box 132)
    - Rubber (Offsite-box 132)
    - Schools and Colleges (Offsite-box 132)
    - Seeds and Plants (Offsite-box 132)
    - Sewing Machines (Offsite-box 132)
    - Sports, Toys and Games (Offsite-box 133)
      Boxing
      Toys
    - Stationery and Valentines (Offsite-box 133)
      Trade and Visiting Cards
    - Stoves, Furnaces, and Ranges (Offsite-box 133)
    - Theatrical Enterprises (Offsite-box 134)
      Curiosities and Wonders
      Fairs
      Sanitary Fairs
      Magic
      Minstrel Shows
      Motion Pictures
      Concerts
    - Tobacco (Offsite-box 135)
      Chewing
      Cigar (Brands and Bands)
      Smoking
    - Toilet Articles and Beauty Aids (Offsite-box 135)
      Face Care
      Hair Care
      Shaving
      Toilet Soap
      Tooth Care
    - Transportation (Offsite-box 136)
      Bicycles
      Carriages
      Roads
      Ships
    - Undertakers (Offsite-box 136)
    - United States Government (Offsite-box 136)
  - Subseries III: LARGE EPHEMERA
    - Agriculture (Folder FF1)
    - Animals (Folder FF2)
    - Antiques (Folder FF3)
    - Art (Folder FF4)
    - Beverages (Folder FF5)
    - Building (Folder FF6)
    - Business (Folder FF7)
    - Clothing (Folder FF8)
    - Clubs and Societies (Folder FF9)
    - Cotton (Folder FF10)
    - Dances and Balls (Folder FF11)
    - Druggists (Folder FF12)
    - Drugs and Medicines (Folder FF13)
    - Dry Goods (Folder FF14)
    - Electricity (Folder FF15)
    - Food (Folder FF16)
    - Furniture (Folder FF17)
    - Hardware (Folder FF18)
    - Hotels and Restaurants (Folder FF19)
    - Household (Folder FF20)
    - Insurance (Folder FF21)
    - Jewelry (Folder FF22)
    - Leather Goods (Folder FF23)
    - Military (Folder FF24)
    - Optical (Folder FF25)
    - Paper (Folder FF26)
    - Periodicals (Folder FF27)
    - Photography (Folder FF28)
    - Printing and Engraving (Folder FF29)
    - Professions and Occupations (Folder FF30)
    - Publications (Folder FF31)
    - Real Estate (Folder FF32)
    - Religion, Philanthropy, and Hospitals (Folder FF33)
    - Schools and Colleges (Folder FF34)
    - Seeds and Plants (Folder FF35)
    - Sewing Machines (Folder FF36)
    - Sports, Toys, and Games (Folder FF37)
    - Stationery and Valentines (Folder FF38)
    - Stoves, Furnaces, and Ranges (Folder FF39)
    - Theatrical Enterprises (Folder FF40)
    - Tobacco (Folder FF41)
    - Toilet Articles and Beauty Aids (Folder FF42)
    - Transportation (Folder FF43)
    - Undertakers, Cemeteries, Coffin Makers, and Funerals (Folder FF44)
    - United States Government (Folder FF45)
- Series III: SHEET MUSIC
  Landauer kept her sheet music separate from other printed ephemera, and it can be found here. This series is arranged by the general subject of the music's cover illustration. The sheet music is not arranged based on what the song is about. However, some music that does not have a cover illustration is filed under the subject of the song along with those songs with illustrations of the same subject. Subjects generally follow the themes of Landauer's scrapbooks (from which some of this music was removed) but are also taken from other collections of sheet music and from the Thesaurus for Graphic Materials subject headings.
  A database on site allows for searching by title or composer.
  - ANIMALS
    - Dogs (Offsite-box III.1, Folder 1)
    - Rats (Offsite-box III.1, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous (Offsite-box III.1, Folder 3)
  - BEVERAGES
    - Beer (Offsite-box III.1, Folder 4-6)
    - Champagne (Offsite-box III.1, Folder 7-9)
    - Drinking Songs (Offsite-box III.1, Folder 10-11)
    - Drunkards (Offsite-box III.1, Folder 12)
    - Liquor (Offsite-box III.1, Folder 13-14)
    - People Drinking (Offsite-box III.1, Folder 15-16)
    - Taverns and Drinking Houses (Offsite-box III.2, Folder 17-18)
    - Temperance (Anti-Temperance) (Offsite-box III.2, Folder 19-20)
    - Temperance (Offsite-box III.2, Folder 21-24)
    - Toasts (Offsite-box III.2, Folder 25-26)
    - Wine (Offsite-box III.2, Folder 27-30)
  - COMIC STRIP CHARACTERS
    - Bringing Up Father (Offsite-box III.3, Folder 31)
    - Brownies (Offsite-box III.3, Folder 32)
    - Lil' Abner (Offsite-box III.3, Folder 33)
    - A-J (Offsite-box III.3, Folder 34)
    - K-N (Offsite-box III.3, Folder 35)
    - O-Z (Offsite-box III.3, Folder 36)
    - Miscellaneous (Offsite-box III.3, Folder 37)
  - DANCES
    - Ballet (Offsite-box III.3, Folder 38)
    - Ballroom (Offsite-box III.3, Folder 39)
    - Barn Dance (Offsite-box III.3, Folder 40-41)
    - Cake Walk (Offsite-box III.4, Folder 42)
    - Can Can (Offsite-box III.4, Folder 43)
    - Charleston (Offsite-box III.4, Folder 44)
    - Fox Trot (Offsite-box III.4, Folder 45)
    - Galop (Offsite-box III.4, Folder 46)
    - Gavotte (Offsite-box III.4, Folder 47)
    - Lancers (Offsite-box III.4, Folder 48)
    - Lancers – By Dodsworth (Offsite-box III.4, Folder 49)
    - Lancers – By Loomis (Offsite-box III.4, Folder 50)
    - Maxixe (Offsite-box III.4, Folder 51)
    - Mazurka (Offsite-box III.4, Folder 52)
    - Mignon (Offsite-box III.4, Folder 53)
    - Minuet (Offsite-box III.4, Folder 54)
    - Polka (Offsite-box III.4, Folder 55-57)
    - Polka Mazurka (Offsite-box III.5, Folder 58)
    - Polonaise (Offsite-box III.5, Folder 59)
    - Quadrille (Offsite-box III.5, Folder 60-61)
    - Rag (Offsite-box III.5, Folder 62)
    - Schottische (Offsite-box III.5, Folder 63)
    - Tango (Offsite-box III.5, Folder 64-65)
    - Two Step (Offsite-box III.5, Folder 66)
    - Waltz (Offsite-box III.5, Folder 67-70)
    - Miscellaneous (Offsite-box III.6, Folder 71-74)
  - EXPOSITIONS
    - Centennial Exposition, 1876 (Offsite-box III.6, Folder 75)
    - Columbian Exposition, 1893 (Offsite-box III.6, Folder 76)
  - FASHIONS
    - Men's (Offsite-box III.6, Folder 77)
    - Women's, 1800-1875 (Offsite-box III.6, Folder 78)
    - Women's, 1876-1900 (Offsite-box III.6, Folder 79)
    - Women's (Bloomers) (Offsite-box III.6, Folder 80)
    - Women's, 1901-1960 (Offsite-box III.6, Folder 81)
    - Women's, undated (Offsite-box III.6, Folder 82)
  - FIRE
    - Firemen (Offsite-box III.7, Folder 83)
    - Fires without Firemen (Offsite-box III.7, Folder 84)
    - Firewagons (Offsite-box III.7, Folder 85)
    - Firewagons at Fires (Offsite-box III.7, Folder 86)
    - No Image (Offsite-box III.7, Folder 87)
  - FLAGS
    - Flags - General (Offsite-box III.7, Folder 88)
  - FOOD
    - Food - General (Offsite-box III.7, Folder 89)
  - GEOGRAPHIC
    This subseries is organized by country, then state, then city.
    - Germany (Offsite-box III.7, Folder 90)
    - Panama and Canal (Offsite-box III.7, Folder 91)
    - Alabama (Offsite-box III.7, Folder 92)
    - Alaska (Offsite-box III.7, Folder 93)
    - Arizona (Offsite-box III.7, Folder 94)
    - California (Offsite-box III.7, Folder 95)
    - Colorado (Offsite-box III.7, Folder 96)
    - Georgia (Offsite-box III.7, Folder 97)
    - Hawaii (Offsite-box III.7, Folder 98)
    - Idaho (Offsite-box III.7, Folder 99)
    - Indiana (Offsite-box III.7, Folder 100)
    - Iowa (Offsite-box III.7, Folder 101)
    - Kansas (Offsite-box III.7, Folder 102)
    - Kentucky (Offsite-box III.7, Folder 103)
    - Michigan (Offsite-box III.7, Folder 104)
    - Minnesota (Offsite-box III.7, Folder 105)
    - Mississippi (Offsite-box III.7, Folder 106)
    - Missouri (Offsite-box III.7, Folder 107)
    - Montana (Offsite-box III.7, Folder 108)
    - Nevada (Offsite-box III.7, Folder 109)
    - New Jersey (Offsite-box III.7, Folder 110)
    - New Mexico (Offsite-box III.7, Folder 111)
    - New York State - General (Offsite-box III.8, Folder 112)
    - New York State - Hudson River (Offsite-box III.8, Folder 113)
    - New York City - Brighton Beach (Offsite-box III.8, Folder 114)
    - New York City - Coney Island (Offsite-box III.8, Folder 115)
    - New York City - Beaches and Resorts (Offsite-box III.8, Folder 116)
    - New York City - Boats and Rivers (Offsite-box III.8, Folder 117)
    - New York City - Bronx (Offsite-box III.8, Folder 118)
    - New York City - Brooklyn (Offsite-box III.8, Folder 119)
    - New York City - Staten Island (Offsite-box III.8, Folder 120)
    - New York City - Brooklyn Bridge (Offsite-box III.8, Folder 121)
    - New York City - Bridges (Offsite-box III.8, Folder 122)
    - New York City - Churches (Offsite-box III.8, Folder 123)
    - New York City - Colleges (Offsite-box III.8, Folder 124)
    - New York City - Crystal Palace (Offsite-box III.8, Folder 125)
    - New York City - Flatiron Building (Offsite-box III.8, Folder 126)
    - New York City - Hippodrome (Offsite-box III.8, Folder 127)
    - New York City - Homes and Apartments (Offsite-box III.8, Folder 128)
    - New York City - Hotels (Offsite-box III.8, Folder 129)
    - New York City - Interiors (Offsite-box III.9, Folder 130)
    - New York City - Theaters (Offsite-box III.9, Folder 131)
    - New York City - Times Building (Offsite-box III.9, Folder 132)
    - New York City - Miscellaneous Buildings (Offsite-box III.9, Folder 133)
    - New York City - Cityscapes (Offsite-box III.9, Folder 134)
    - New York City - Chinatown (Offsite-box III.9, Folder 135)
    - New York City - Harlem (Offsite-box III.9, Folder 136)
    - New York City - Times Square (Offsite-box III.9, Folder 137)
    - New York City - Miscellaneous Neighborhoods (Offsite-box III.9, Folder 138)
    - New York City - Central Park (Offsite-box III.9, Folder 139)
    - New York City - Miscellaneous Parks (Offsite-box III.9, Folder 140)
    - New York City - the Bowery (Offsite-box III.10, Folder 141)
    - New York City - Broadway (Offsite-box III.10, Folder 142)
    - New York City - Wall Street (Offsite-box III.10, Folder 143)
    - New York City - Miscellaneous Streets (Offsite-box III.10, Folder 144)
    - New York City - Ellis Island and the Statue of Liberty (Offsite-box III.10, Folder 145)
    - New York City - People (2 folders) (Offsite-box III.10, Folder 146-147)
    - New York City - Miscellaneous (Offsite-box III.10, Folder 148)
    - Niagara Falls (Offsite-box III.10, Folder 149)
    - Ohio (Offsite-box III.11, Folder 150)
    - Oregon (Offsite-box III.11, Folder 151)
    - Pennsylvania (Offsite-box III.11, Folder 152)
    - Rhode Island (Offsite-box III.11, Folder 153)
    - Texas (Offsite-box III.11, Folder 154)
    - Washington (Offsite-box III.11, Folder 155)
    - Wyoming (Offsite-box III.11, Folder 156)
    - Western United States - Conestogas (Offsite-box III.11, Folder 157)
    - Western United States - Couples (Offsite-box III.11, Folder 158)
    - Western United States - Cowboys (Offsite-box III.11, Folder 159)
    - Western United States - Cowboys in Groups (Offsite-box III.11, Folder 160)
    - Western United States - Cowgirls (Offsite-box III.11, Folder 161)
    - Western United States - Landscapes (Offsite-box III.11, Folder 162)
    - Western United States - Miscellaneous (2 folders) (Offsite-box III.11, Folder 163-164)
  - LANDSCAPES
    - Landscapes - General (Offsite-box III.11, Folder 165)
  - MILITARY
    - Army (Offsite-box III.12, Folder 166)
    - Confederate (Offsite-box III.12, Folder 167)
    - Military (Offsite-box III.12, Folder 168)
    - Navy (Offsite-box III.12, Folder 169)
    - Seventh Regiment (2 folders) (Offsite-box III.12, Folder 170-171)
  - MUSICAL INSTRUMENTS
    - Multiple Instruments (Offsite-box III.12, Folder 172)
    - Piano (Offsite-box III.12, Folder 173)
    - Miscellaneous Instruments (Offsite-box III.12, Folder 174)
  - NEWSPAPERS
    - New York Herald (Offsite-box III.12, Folder 175)
    - Miscellaneous Newspapers (Offsite-box III.12, Folder 176)
  - PATRIOTIC
    - Patriotic - General (Offsite-box III.12, Folder 177)
  - PEOPLE
    - Children (Offsite-box III.13, Folder 178)
    - Couples - Dancing (Offsite-box III.13, Folder 179)
    - Couples - General (Offsite-box III.13, Folder 180-181)
    - Africans (Offsite-box III.13, Folder 182)
    - African-Americans - Dancing (4 folders) (Offsite-box III.13, Folder 183-186)
    - African-Americans - Entertainers (Offsite-box III.13, Folder 187)
    - African-Americans - Individuals (Offsite-box III.13, Folder 188)
    - African-Americans - Military (Offsite-box III.13, Folder 189)
    - African-Americans - Miscellaneous (2 folders) (Offsite-box III.13, Folder 190-191)
    - Ethnic Groups - General (Offsite-box III.13, Box 192)
    - Asian-Americans (Offsite-box III.14, Folder 193)
    - Native Americans (3 folders) (Offsite-box III.14, Folder 194-196)
    - Groups - General (2 folders) (Offsite-box III.14, Folder 197-198)
    - Men (4 folders) (Offsite-box III.14, Folder 199-202)
    - Little People [Midgets] (Offsite-box III.14, Folder 203)
    - Portraits - Fanny Elssler (Offsite-box III.14, Folder 204)
    - Portraits - Adeline Patti (Offsite-box III.15, Folder 205)
    - Portraits - Anna Pavlova (Offsite-box III.15, Folder 206)
    - Portraits - John Philip Sousa (Offsite-box III.15, Folder 207)
    - Professions - General (Offsite-box III.15, Folder 208)
    - Organ Grinders (Offsite-box III.15, Folder 209)
    - Police (Offsite-box III.15, Folder 210)
    - Politicians (Offsite-box III.15, Folder 211)
    - Religious Groups (Offsite-box III.15, Folder 212)
    - Women - General (4 folders) (Offsite-box III.15, Folder 213-216)
    - Women - the "New Woman" (Offsite-box III.15, Folder 217)
    - Women - Suffragists and Suffragettes (Offsite-box III.15, Folder 218)
  - PRESIDENTS and POLITICIANS
    - Adams (Offsite-box III.16, Folder 219)
    - Arthur (Offsite-box III.16, Folder 220)
    - Blaine (Offsite-box III.16, Folder 221)
    - Clay (Offsite-box III.16, Folder 222)
    - Cleveland (Offsite-box III.16, Folder 223)
    - Coolidge (Offsite-box III.16, Folder 224)
    - Cox (Offsite-box III.16, Folder 225)
    - Dewey (Offsite-box III.16, Folder 226)
    - Dimmock (Offsite-box III.16, Folder 227)
    - Eisenhower (Offsite-box III.16, Folder 228)
    - Fillmore (Offsite-box III.16, Folder 229)
    - Garfield (Offsite-box III.16, Folder 230)
    - Fremont (Offsite-box III.16, Folder 231)
    - Grant (3 folders) (Offsite-box III.16, Folder 232-234)
    - Hancock (Offsite-box III.16, Folder 235)
    - Harding (Offsite-box III.16, Folder 236)
    - Harrison (Offsite-box III.16, Folder 237)
    - Hayes (Offsite-box III.16, Folder 238)
    - Hoover (Offsite-box III.16, Folder 239)
    - Jackson (Offsite-box III.16, Folder 240)
    - Jefferson (Offsite-box III.16, Folder 241)
    - Lincoln (2 folders) (Offsite-box III.16, Folder 242-243)
    - McKinley (2 folders) (Offsite-box III.17, Folder 244-245)
    - Parker (Offsite-box III.17, Folder 246)
    - Roosevelt, Franklin Delano (Offsite-box III.17, Folder 247)
    - Roosevelt, Theodore (2 folders) (Offsite-box III.17, Folder 248-250)
    - Smith (Offsite-box III.17, Folder 251)
    - Taft (Offsite-box III.17, Folder 252)
    - Taylor (Offsite-box III.17, Folder 253)
    - Washington (2 folders) (Offsite-box III.17, Folder 254-255)
    - Wilson (Offsite-box III.17, Folder 256)
  - SONGS
    - Marches (Offsite-box III.18, Folder 257)
    - from Motion Pictures/Movies (Offsite-box III.18, Folder 258)
    - from Theater/Theatrical Productions (2 folders) (Offsite-box III.18, Folder 259-260)
  - SPORTS
    - Sports -General (Offsite-box III.18, Folder 261)
  - TECHNOLOGY
    - Technology - General (Offsite-box III.18, Folder 262)
    - Phonograph (Offsite-box III.18, Folder 263)
    - Telephone (Offsite-box III.18, Folder 264)
    - Television (Offsite-box III.18, Folder 265)
    - Telegraph (Offsite-box III.18, Folder 266)
  - TRANSPORTATION
    - Airplanes (Offsite-box III.19, Folder 267)
    - Automobiles (Offsite-box III.19, Folder 268)
    - Railroads (Offsite-box III.19, Folder 269)
    - Steamships (Offsite-box III.19, Folder 270)
    - Sailing Ships (Offsite-box III.19, Folder 271)
    - Subways (Offsite-box III.19, Folder 272)
    - Trolleys (Offsite-box III.19, Folder 273)
    - Miscellaneous Transportation (2 folders) (Offsite-box III.19, Folder 274-275)
  - WARS
    - Spanish-American War (5 folders) (Offsite-box III.20, Folder 276-280)
      Includes:
      Admirals Dewey and Randall
      Battle of Manila
      Cuba
      U.S.S. Maine
      Navy
    - World War I - Aftermath (7 folders) (Offsite-box III.20, Folder 281-287)
      Coming Home
      Europe
      League of Nations
      Veterans
      Victory and Peace
    - World War I - Allies (6 folders) (Offsite-box III.20, Folder 288-293)
      Belgium
      France
      Ireland
    - World War I - Army and Navy (3 folders) (Offsite-box III.21, Folder 294-296)
    - World War I - Enemies (Offsite-box III.21, Folder 297)
    - World War I - Fathers at War (Offsite-box III.21, Folder 298)
    - World War I - Heroes "Over There" (2 folders) (Offsite-box III.21, Folder 299-300)
    - World War I - Home (3 folders) (Offsite-box III.21, Folder 301-303)
      Civilian Men
      Families Missing Soldiers
      Soldiers Missing Families
    - World War I - Mothers (3 folders) (Offsite-box III.21, Folder 304-306)
    - World War I - Optimistic Battle Songs (2 folders) (Offsite-box III.22, Folder 307-308)
    - World War I - Patriotism (7 folders) (Offsite-box III.22, Folder 309-316)
      Eagles
      General Patriotism
      Uncle Sam
    - World War I - Peace Hopes (Offsite-box III.22, Folder 317)
    - World War I - General John Pershing (Offsite-box III.22, Folder 318)
    - World War I - Pre-war (Offsite-box III.23, Folder 319)
    - World War I - Romances (Offsite-box III.23, Folder 320)
    - World War I - Sacrifices at Home (Offsite-box III.23, Folder 321)
    - World War I - Service Organizations (4 folders) (Offsite-box III.23, Folder 322-325)
      Red Cross
      Salvation Army
      Soldiers' Camp Life
    - World War I - Sweethearts (2 folders) (Offsite-box III.23, Folder 326-329)
    - World War I - Troops Leaving the U.S. (Offsite-box III.23, Folder 330)
    - World War I - The Unknown Soldier (Offsite-box III.23, Folder 331)
    - World War I - The U.S. in France (Offsite-box III.23, Folder 332)
    - World War I - Volunteering and Drafting (Offsite-box III.23, Folder 333)
    - World War I - Miscellaneous (Offsite-box III.23, Folder 334)
  - MISCELLANEOUS
    - Sheet Music with No Images/Miscellaneous (8 folders) (Offsite-box III.24, Folder 335-342)
- Series IV: WEICHSEL TOBACCO COLLECTION
  This series is comprised of scrapbooks of tobacco product packaging, including those for cigarettes, cigars, loose tobacco, chewing tobacco, pipe tobacco. Also included are cigar bands, matchbook covers, newspaper clippings, and pieces of correspondence between Weichsel and the various agents from whom he procured either packaging or information about tobacco production and distribution in the various countries. The packaging is largely undated, and though there are pieces from the nineteenth century, most of the pieces appear to be mid-twentieth century, contemporary with Weichsel's collecting in the 1950s.
  It is currently unclear whether Landauer herself acquired this collection before her death (as she often did) or if it was donated to the Society at a later date. Because of the ambiguity of the historical record, it has been kept within the confines of the Landauer collection.
  The bulk of the collection is material from international tobacco companies. Countries represented include:
  Aden
  Afghanistan
  Algeria
  Andorra
  Angola
  Argentina
  Australia (including Tasmania)
  Austria
  Azores
  Belize
  Bolivia
  Brazil
  Bulgaria
  Burma
  Cambodia
  Cameroon
  Chile
  China
  Colombia
  Costa Rica
  Czechoslovakia
  Denmark
  Ecuador
  Egypt
  El Salvador
  Estonia
  Ethiopia
  Fiji
  Finland
  France (including Reunion)
  Gambia
  Germany
  Gibraltar
  Great Britain: England; Ireland (including Northern Ireland); Scotland
  Greece
  Greenland
  Guatemala
  Haiti
  Honduras
  Hong Kong
  Hungary
  India
  Indonesia
  Iran
  Iraq
  Israel
  Italy (including Trieste)
  Jamaica
  Japan
  Jordan
  Kenya
  Korea
  Kuwait
  Lebanon
  Luxembourg
  Libya
  Madagascar
  Malaysia
  Malta
  Mexico
  Monaco
  Morocco (Spanish Morocco)
  Mozambique
  Netherlands
  New Zealand
  Nicaragua
  Nigeria
  Norway
  Oman
  Pakistan
  Panama
  Paraguay
  Peru
  Philippines
  Poland
  Portugal (including Madeira Island)
  Puerto Rico
  Romania
  Russia
  Saudi Arabia
  Senegal
  Singapore
  Somalia
  Southern Africa countries (including Nyasaland, Northern Rhodesia, Southern Rhodesia, Transvaal)
  Spain
  Sri Lanka
  Sweden
  Switzerland
  Taiwan
  Tanzania (Tanganyika)
  Thailand
  Trinidad
  Tunisia
  Turkey
  Uganda
  Uruguay
  Venezuela
  Vietnam
  Yemen
  Yugoslavia
  - Candy Cigarettes (Offsite-box WT 1, Box IV.1 - IV.2)
  - Cut-Outs (Offsite-box WT 1, Box IV.2)
  - International tobacco companies (1 of 9) (Offsite-box WT 1, Box IV.3)
  - International tobacco companies (2 of 9) (Offsite-box WT 2, Box IV.4 - IV.6)
  - International tobacco companies (3 of 9) (Offsite-box WT 3, Box IV.7 - IV.9)
  - International tobacco companies (4 of 9) (Offsite-box WT 4, Box IV.10 - IV.12)
  - International tobacco companies (5 of 9) (Offsite-box WT 5, Box IV.13 - IV.15)
  - International tobacco companies (6 of 9) (Offsite-box WT 6, Box IV.16 - IV.18)